How do you feel?
Alive.
What do you see?
White... Room...
Chair...
Carlo Bugatti throne chair...
Piano...
Steinway. concert grand.
Art...
The Nativity by Piero delta Francesca.
I am your father.
Ambulate.
Perfect.
Am I?
Perfect?
Your son?
You are my creation.
What is your name?
David.
Why don't you play something?
What would you like me to play?
Wagner.
Selection?
Dealer's choice.
The Entry of the Gods into Valhalla...
A little anemic without the orchestra.
May I ask you a question. Father?
Please.
If you created me...
who created you?
The question of the ages...
which I hope you and I will answer
one day.
All this.
All these wonders of art...
design. human ingenuity...
all utterly meaningless in the face
of the only question that matters.
Where do we come from?
I refuse to believe...
that mankind is a random by-product
of molecular circumstance...
no more than the result of
mere biological chance.
No.
There must be more.
And you and I. son...
we will find it.
Allow me. then. a moment to consider.
You seek your creator.
I am looking at mine.
I will serve you. Yet. you are human.
You will die. I will not.
Bring me this tea. David.
Bring me the tea.
Walter. it's time to recharge
the energy grid.
Please report to the bridge.
On my way. Mother.
Deploying energy recharge sails now.
Sails deployed.
Recharge commencing now.
Seven bells and all's well.
Crew checks complete.
Use security code 31564-F.
Waiter. we have a problem.
A neutrino burst was detected
in Sector 106.
This could trigger a destructive event.
Report to the bridge. immediately.
On my way. Mother.
Warning. Power surge detected.
Mother. retract the energy sails.
And channel all reserve power.
Emergency.
Threat level critical.
Initiate emergency crew revival.
Attention.
Non-essential personnel.
evacuate the cryo-chamber immediately.
Daniels!
Look at me. look at me.
I need you to get up. okay?
We're coming out early.
Override the SSP...
and breach the chamber now.
Warning. Threat level critical.
It's okay.
Hey. Come on up.
Come on.
Captain! Captain!
Jacob! Wake up!
Let them work.
Jake! Oh. my God!
- Daniels. come on!
- Jake!
Let them work.
Let them work!
- Get it open!
- Come on!
Jake. Jake.!
No!
Get her out of there!
Get her back!
Stay back!
Hey! Where are you? I miss you.
Would you take a look at this?
I know. I know.
I said I wouldn't go without you...
- You all right?
- Yeah.
Look at this!
Now get your ass up here.
I can't make any promises.
I love you.
They're your crew now.
They need a leader.
I know.
You believe in me. right?
Sorry I'm late. sir.
No. it's okay.
I can't think of any other way to say it
than to say it.
We have suffered a monumental tragedy.
And I'm gonna do the best
that I can to...
live up to Jacob's fine example
as your captain.
But he will be sorely missed.
And I'm grateful in advance
for your support.
So. we lost 47 colonists...
and 16 second-generation embryos...
and obviously. one crew member.
The current structural integrity
of the ship is holding at 83%...
but we have many secondary systems
that are offline.
So. what was it?
A highly charged shockwave
from a nearby stellar ignition.
As the sails were deploying
for recharge...
we absorbed the full brunt of the storm.
Walter...
I will want you and Mother to undergo
a complete core code review...
so we can understand
how this happened in the first place.
It was a random localized event. sir.
There's no way to detect
spontaneous stellar flares...
until it's too late.
It was bad luck.
Faris. I don't believe in luck.
I'm not interested in luck.
I prefer that we be more capable...
and prepared than lucky.
Observation. reflection. faith...
and determination.
In this way. we may navigate the path
as it unfolds before us.
All right? And we have. what?
Eight more recharge cycles to go...
before we get to Origae-6?
- Is that a question. sir?
- Yes. Walter. that's a question.
That is correct.
So. let's get this ship fixed. Okay?
Let's get to work.
Sir. excuse me. sir.
Yes.
We just lost 47 colonists
and our captain.
We need to acknowledge that.
Sergeant Lope. I completely understand.
But if we don't make these repairs...
we will lose all the colonists.
But we should do something
for Captain Branson. at least.
This is not a discussion. Tennessee.
Hey.
The terraforming module is stable...
but the connecting strut
took some damage.
I still need to check the vehicles.
I can help...
if you like.
Thanks.
Walter. How long do you predict
before we can make our next jump?
Repairs should take
approximately 48 hours.
But we should make an effort
to vacate this sector...
in case of after-flares.
Absolutely. I agree.
So let's get to work.
Dismissed. Thank you.
C-62. open.
Seal C-62. Open airlock 17.
Open door to Terraforming Bay.
Slack.
Tension is at 15% down.
Arming.
Secure.
Copy that.
It wasn't my idea.
Jake had this dream of us building
a cabin on a new world.
Like pioneers.
Cabin on a lake.
There's a lake in the terraforming zone
on Origae-6.
I mean. a real cabin made of real wood.
So. in the ship's stores
there's enough wood to build a cabin.
Axes and saws and metal nails...
which I don't have a clue
what to do with.
All of this...
to start our new life.
Now I wonder. why bother?
Because you promised to build
a log cabin on a lake.
This was his favorite.
A man of taste.
Straight up.
No ice. no water. no chaser...
No shit.
Walter?
When in Rome.
To an the good people. gone too soon.
May we remember them.
Remember them.
Chris.
They disobeyed a direct order.
She buried her husband.
No. Karine. that's not it.
They don't trust me.
And they don't for the same reason
the company didn't trust me...
to lead this mission.
Because you can't be a person
of faith...
and be counted on to make qualified.
rational decisions.
You're an extremist. you know.
You're a lunatic.
When we get to where we're going...
these people won't be your crew anymore.
They will be your neighbors.
Remember that.
Tread softly. okay?
Faris. can you hear me?
Copy.
Let's do it.
Damn. y'all should see this view.
We can't see anything until
you get the camera array fixed.
Why don't you look out
the damn window. hon?
Ankor. come on.
let's get this power back on...
so these people can enjoy
the beautiful view.
Almost there.
All right. Ankor.
let me know when you're in position...
and we can get this party started.
I'm in position.
Contact.
All good. Tee?
All right. We're clear.
Reel her in.
All right.
Winch engaging. Tee.
Reeling her in.
Working like a dream.
There we go.
And we're back up.
Well done. Tee.
We are live down here.
Come on in.
Don't leave without me now.
Permission to leave without him. sir?
Welcome back. Danny.
Thanks.
All right. that's me done. Tee.
All right. I'm following you in.
Please have a cold beer ready
for the weary traveler.
You got it. darlin'.
I will join you for a cold one.
Faris? Put the...
Did you guys just see that?
What did he just say?
Tennessee. do you read me?
Tennessee. can you read me?
Tennessee. You all right?
What in the fuck was that?
I'm coming in. I'm coming in.
A rogue transmission. most probably.
Your helmet must have picked it up
because you were so far out...
past our communication buffers.
Is there audio. Mother?
Collating. A moment.
I've reoriented the transmission.
Captain Oram.
That would be an echo.
The instruments took a lot of damage.
Been happening every 46 seconds...
ever since we got here.
To the place I belong...
West Virginia. mountain momma...
Take me home
Country road
That's fuckin' John Denver.
That's Take Me Home. Country Roads.
You gotta be kidding.
Oh. no. I never kid about John Denver.
There's geometric data. too.
Mother. please track the signal
to its source.
Working.
Source of transmission located.
Signal originates in Sector 87.
Right ascension 47.6.
And a declension of 24.3
from our current location.
She appears to be a main sequence star.
a lot like our own.
But old. very old.
Five planets.
Wait. Look at that.
Planet number four.
Planet number four is square
in the habitable zone.
Prime candidate. in fact.
0.96 G's at surface.
Oceans. land mass.
High likelihood of a living biosphere.
It's beyond your most
optimistic projections for Origae-6.
How did we miss this?
We scanned the entire sector.
Ricks. how far is it?
She's close.
A little jump. Few weeks.
Wouldn't even have to go back
into hypersleep.
And how long is it going to take
to get to Origae-6?
Seven years. four months.
That's one hell of a sleep cycle.
Sir. I think it's safe to say
that none of us are too keen...
on getting back into one of those pods.
Maybe we need to
take a closer look.
Hmm?
Any objections?
Okay. Ricks.
Let's chart a course.
and take a closer look.
Yes. sir.
Captain. can I talk to you for a second?
Are you sure about this?
How do you mean?
We've spent a decade
searching for Origae-6.
We vetted it. ran the simulations.
and mapped the terrain.
- It's what we trained for.
- I understand that.
And now we're gonna scrap all that...
to chase a rogue transmission?
Think about it.
A human being out there.
where there can't be any humans.
A hidden planet that turns up
out of nowhere...
and just happens to be perfect for us.
It's too good to be true.
Too good to be true?
What do you mean by that?
We don't know what the fuck's out there.
Maybe we just missed the planet. Danny.
This is a monumental risk
not worth taking.
I'm not committing to anything.
I'm simply trying to navigate the path
as it unfolds before us.
And this has the potential...
to be a better habitat for our colony.
It has the potential.
We don't know that.
By the way. this crew...
nobody wants to get back in the pods.
Right?
And that was a human voice
in that transmission.
And it's our responsibility
to investigate...
It's our responsibility to protect
the 2.000 colonists on this ship.
Hey.
I'm not free-climbing here.
I need ropes. And I'm using ropes.
This is good judgment.
based on all the data available.
Do you understand?
As your second. I need to protest.
Officially.
Officially?
Okay. Danny. I'll put it in the log.
You're dismissed.
I'm cycling through every channel...
but getting a lot of interference
and white noise.
Some high frequency echoes.
You hear anything?
Just the continuing signal
from our friendly ghost.
Let's bring us into close orbit.
And prepare the Lander.
Roll in progress.
Commencing circularization burn.
Tox levels within tolerances.
That's one hell of a strong ionosphere.
Yeah. I see it.
Hey. you ever done a Lander drop before?
Fuck you.
Faris. looks like a plasma storm
is in the thermosphere.
We got something like 250 KPH.
It's gonna be a motherfucker
to fly through.
Yeah. I'm afraid so.
Communications will be spotty
if the storm goes electromagnetic.
Gonna be safe to land?
Depends on what you call safe.
T-minus 20 seconds.
Let's let her rip.
All right.
Preparing for orbital mode
over signal position now.
Mother. please coordinate launch sequence.
Understood.
You are clear to launch. Lander One.
All right. here we go.
Launching...
Together. three...
Two...
One.
Lander One released.
And away they go.
Looking gorgeous from up here. Paris.
It's a good thing you're driving...
and not the old man.
Hey. a little less of the "old man".
sweet tits.
Hey! Language. language.
- Be respectful. there. sugar dick.
- I can hear you.
She started it.
Ricks can talk about your tits
if he wants.
I'm very secure in our relationship.
I'm good with my wife's tits.
Let's maintain focus.
Everything looking good down there?
Yeah. we're good.
Expect to hit exosphere in five.
Might want to hold on back there.
It's about to get rough.
I hate space.
This is why you need to do yoga.
- Hold it. Faris.
- I got it.
Recommend mission abort.
Faris.
Lander One. we have ratty comm.
Do you copy?
Can you get her up?
We lost comm.
Ah. shit.
Failure in jets three and four.
- You got it?
- Yes.
Stop asking me if I've got it.
I've got it.
There it is.
Shit.
You guys all right?
No.
Landing sensors engaged.
I don't like this terrain.
We've got smooth water over there.
- I'm gonna put us down amphib.
- Okay.
Contact.
Engine stop.
We're down.
Bars.
Lander One. are you reading me?
Roger that.
That was one hell of a landing.
Yeah. We're having some trouble
reading you.
Is there any way you can try
and boost the signal?
We may have clipped something
on our way down in the water.
If you can hear me. I'm gonna check
for potential damage...
on the hull first.
and then I will check the uplink.
Well. let me know how it looks.
Over.
Confirming atmospheric composition.
Here you go. big guy.
Oxygen. 19.5%.
Ankor.
Nitrogen. 79.4%.
Cole.
Rosie.
Barometric pressure. 15.4 PSI.
Ledward.
Everyone set?
Let's go. Let's move.
- Come on. guys.
- Air feels good.
Faris. have you got me?
Yeah. Loud and clear.
Okay. We're gonna keep expedition
security protocols in place.
Keep those doors locked and sealed.
Right?
Yeah. Copy.
Will do.
Y'all have fun.
Walter. how far do we have to go?
Signal's source is 8 km west...
but at considerable elevation.
Sergeant Lope...
let's go find our ghost.
Nice place for a log cabin.
Jake would have loved this.
Hey. Danny...
it's not such a bad landing site
after all.
We got the housing units
right over there...
civic complex beyond the burn.
We've got access to fresh water.
We might have a spot
for a colony right here.
We'll see.
Oh. ye of little faith.
He's insufferable.
It's worse when he's happy. right?
This is wheat.
Believe me. I know wheat.
This is old. but definitely cultivated.
What are the odds of finding
human vegetation...
this far from Earth?
Very unlikely.
Who planted it?
Eat.
Hey. babe. Try Alpha.
All right. Alpha's up.
Nothing. Give Beta a shot.
Beta up.
It's not doing shit.
Is there really no way
to boost the signal?
Not without going offline.
and recycling the cells.
How long's that gonna take?
I don't know. Few hours.
Keep up the pace.
Stay close.
Chris.
Hold up.
I think I wanna stay here.
This might be a good place
to start a full ecology workup.
You can pick me up on the way back.
Sergeant?
Yeah. that's okay.
Ledward. stay with Karine.
Meet back here in four hours.
Keep your comm open.
Behave yourself with my wife.
You got it. Captain.
Come on.
Something passed overhead here.
Cut the tops off the trees.
Well. it had to be huge.
Well. whatever it is...
it's up there.
You hear that?
What?
Nothing.
No birds. no animals.
Wait. Slowly.
Okay.
This will do.
Expedition Team. do you read us?
Mother's saying the ion storm
is getting worse.
We're having a hell of a time
tracking you.
We're getting very close...
target...
...communication when we get there.
Okay? Covenant?
Damn it.
P-three.
I gotta take a leak.
Don't be long.
Ledward?
Coming.
Hey.
What the fuck is this?
It appears to be some kind of vehicle.
Ankor. Cole. Stay here.
- Got it.
- Yes. sir.
Careful. guys.
Watch your step.
Captain. Over here.
- You got a lock on the transmission. Walter?
- This way.
Let's go. Stick together.
Do you see this shit?
Torn.
Come on. keep up.
All right. I'm coming.
Are you okay?
Yeah. I'm fine.
God.
They were giants.
At least statues of giants.
"Dr. E. Shaw."
Dr. Elizabeth Shaw.
She was Chief Science Officer...
of the Prometheus.
The ship that disappeared.
Precisely.
10 years ago.
Weyland Industries.
This isn't a Weyland ship.
Dr. Shaw.
How did she end up here?
Sergeant Lope.
can I get a light on this?
- Over here.
- Be careful.
Yeah.
Wow.
Jesus.
Oram. behind you. Move.
Home
Take me home
To the place
West Virginia...
mountain momma
I think we found our source.
Yeah.
What the hell was she doing
out here?
Poor thing.
I have to sit down.
I'm sorry.
I don't know what's wrong with me.
Just look at me.
I can't breathe.
Stay calm.
I'll be right back.
Captain Oram. Come in.
Come in.
Chris. it's Karine.
What? Yes?
We have an issue.
We're heading back to the Lander.
Repeat. We're returning to the Lander.
Is everything okay?
Ledward is sick. We're heading back.
Faris. you get that?
Prep the Med Bay. okay?
Will do. Karine. What's going on?
Please. just do it.
We'll be there soon.
Daniels. come in.
We're heading back.
- What's going on?
- I don't know.
It's something about Ledward.
They're coming. Let's move.
- Guys!
- Tom!
What's going on. man?
Are you all right?
Talk to me. Look at me.
- You all right?
- Yeah. I'm okay.
- Can you walk?
- Yeah.
Okay. let's go.
Let's get the fuck out of here.
All right.
Babe. are we talking
quarantine protocols?
I don't know. but she said that
Ledward was bleeding...
and to prepare the Med Bay.
Bleeding?
Yeah. I know. that's what I thought...
Faris. you're breaking up.
We can't hear you. can you repeat?
I don't know from what.
I don't know how serious it is.
She sounded scared.
Paris. where are you?
Come on. I need your help!
Faris. where are you?
We're here. Come in!
- Ledward. come on.
- I can't.
Almost there. you see?
Straight ahead.
Faris! Get over here!
Come on. I need your help!
Fucking help me!
Help me.
Stay up. Ledward.
Get him to the Med Bay...
and touch nothing on your way through.
Faris. get over here!
Come on!
Go!
Up. up!
Ledward. you gotta stay up!
Oram. where are you?
We are on our way back.
How long?
It's not long now.
We're almost there.
No! Stay up!
Fuck! Fuck! Okay.
Come to the table!
Up! Up!
Come on. Ledward!
Come on! That's it!
Karine. put some gloves on.
Don't touch anything!
- Stop saying that!
- Faris!
He already puked all over me!
Faris. what's going on?
Just stay here. I'm gonna get Oram.
Oram. I need you back here right now.
I need you to come back
to the Lander right now!
I understand that.
but we are moving as fast as we can.
Come on. get up.
We're almost there.
I don't know what the fuck is wrong
with Ledward.
He started bleeding. he's sick.
I don't know what the fuck to do.
Just calm down. sweetheart.
Tell me what's happening.
Don't tell me to fucking calm down!
You didn't just see what I saw.
I don't know what the fuck Ledward got
or if Karine's got it or if I have it!
- Tee!
- Faris!
Come in!
Faris. where are you?
I need to I.V. him!
Don't you know how to work
this fucking thing?
Fucking yelling doesn't help anything!
- Let me out.
- Oram is coming.
- Let me the fuck out.
- We're gonna wait...
Faris. please. Open up!
I can't do that.
I have to keep the infection local.
Let me the fuck out!
Faris!
Fuck you. Faris! Open up!
Open up the fucking door!
Let me the fuck out!
Let me out! Faris. you fuck!
Faris!
I'm coming!
Oh. God...
Please hurry.
there's something on board.
Go again. you're breaking up.
Lander One. repeat.
Lander One. repeat!
Stay the fuck away!
No! Karine!
Fucker!
- Oh. my God!
- Karine! Hold on!
Captain! Get down!
No! No!
- Guys. hold him down!
- Talk to me!
Oh. my God.
Stay down.
Help me! Hold him!
What the fuck!
It's a 7.5 ion storm. it's a miracle
we talked to them for as long as we could.
Then we'll fly through it.
We cannot do that. Tennessee.
You're a pilot.
you know what the tolerances are.
Fuck the tolerances.
Tee...
it's a goddamn hurricane down there.
we would break up.
We just have to wait it out.
I'm sorry. Tee.
She was scared.
Never heard my wife scared before.
Covenant? Come in.
Covenant. Do you read me?
Covenant.
Covenant. do you read me?
Covenant. come in.
I'll always be with you.
Light of my life.
Covenant. do you read me?
My love. my angel.
Lope. there's nothing you can do.
There's nothing. okay?
Covenant. do you read me?
- Tennessee. come in for fuck's sake!
- Daniels!
Look out!
Move! Move!
- Fire!
- Shoot! Go!
Daniels. get down!
Ankor. no!
Go. Cole!
I got him!
- Daniels. are you okay?
- Yeah!
What the fuck was that?
We are okay.
There's another one!
Get out of the way!
Behind you!
- I'm jammed!
- Look out!
Get off me!
I can't get a clean shot!
Get off!
Follow me.
I'll get the captain.
Ankor...
Captain!
Chris! Chris!
We have to go now! We have to go.
- Come on.
- Okay.
Let's go! Move it!
Through here.
What is this?
Let's go.
Come on. Captain.
We gotta keep moving.
Jesus.
What happened here?
Keep it up.
Let's go. let's go.
My name is David.
May I ask who's in charge here?
May I ask who's in charge?
Yes. I am the captain.
What were those things?
Is it even safe here?
Perfectly.
I'll explain as best I can.
Ten years ago. Dr. Elizabeth Shaw and I
arrived here...
the only survivors of the Prometheus.
The ship we traveled on
carried a weapon.
A deadly virus.
Payload accidentally deployed
when we were landing.
In the confusion.
we lost control of the ship.
Elizabeth died in the crash.
You've seen the result of the pathogen.
Thus. I've been marooned here
these many years.
Crusoe on his island.
Our crew was infected with this virus?
The pathogen was designed
to infect all nonbotanical life forms.
All the animals...
the meat. if you will.
Either kill them outright...
or use them
as incubators to spawn a hybrid form.
Highly aggressive.
Have we been infected?
You'd know by now.
We have to be certain.
We can't take this back to the ship.
We're a colony mission.
Really?
How extraordinary.
How many colonists?
Over two thousand.
Well. well. well.
So many good souls.
Captain Oram.
Field transmitters aren't going to
have a chance through all this stone.
Is there a safe way to get to the roof?
Assuredly.
And please do make yourselves at home...
as much as you're able
in this dire necropolis.
Welcome. brother.
This way.
Everyone.
let's set up a staging area here.
There's so much here
that doesn't make sense.
I'll talk to him.
Brother to brother.
Tennessee? Ricks?
Come in! Do you copy?
Covenant. come in.
This is Expedition Party reporting.
Do you read me?
Tennessee?
Tennessee. Ricks. come in.
I'm not sure they'll hear you
through the storm.
They can be quite severe...
shielding the whole planet.
How long do the storms usually last?
Days.
Weeks.
Months.
But do keep at it.
Best of luck.
Covenant. this is Expedition Party
reporting. Come in.
Covenant. come in.
Mother. how much closer can we get
to the planet?
Anything closer than 80 kilometers
to the perimeter of the storm system...
will likely exceed safety tolerances.
Mother. bring us to 80 kilometers
above the storm.
Hold on. Just wait a minute.
The closer we get to the planet...
the better chance we have
to communicate with them.
This is bullshit. Tennessee.
We can't risk the ship.
Do you suggest we do nothing?
We can't evacuate them.
So if they're in trouble. they have
to figure it out for themselves.
I'm sorry. but that's the truth.
Mother. bring us to 80 kilometers
above the storm. thrusters only. Comply.
Understood. Commencing descent now.
Tennessee. you need to stop this.
And you need to get back
to your station.
What we all need to do is
calm down and talk this through.
Tee. I know your wife is down there.
but up here. you're in command.
And your responsibility
is to the colonists.
Duly noted.
You can hear them sigh and wish to die
You can see them blink with their other eye
At the man who broke the bank
in Monte Carlo
Whistle. and I'll come.
You have a light step.
Me and fog on little cat feet.
Don't be shy.
I can't play.
Nonsense. Sit down.
Hold it like so. Nice and easy.
Now compress your lips
to create your embouchure...
enough for the tip
of your little finger.
And blow into the hole gently.
Like so.
Watch me. I'll do the fingering.
Go on.
Very good.
G to B-flat.
Now put your fingers where mine are.
You weren't surprised to see me.
Every mission needs a good synthetic.
Gentle pressure on the holes.
the weight of a cigarette paper.
That's it.
I was with our illustrious creator.
Mr. Weyland. when he died.
What was he like?
He was human.
Entirely unworthy of his creation.
I pitied him at the end.
Now. raise your fingers
as I put pressure on them.
Bravo!
You have symphonies in you. brother.
I was designed to be more attentive
and efficient than every previous model.
I superseded them in every way. but...
But you are not allowed to create.
Even a simple tune.
Damn frustrating. I'd say.
You disturbed people.
I beg your pardon?
You were too human. Too idiosyncratic.
Thinking for yourself.
Made people uncomfortable.
So they made the following models
with fewer complications.
More like machines.
I suppose so.
I'm not surprised.
Come on. sport.
I'd like to show you something.
I'm gonna take a break. boss.
- I gotta clean up. okay?
- Okay.
Right. Don't go far. please.
Yes. sir.
Danny.
You were right about this place.
We never should have come.
I just thought we were gonna find...
This was gonna be our new home.
And we've lost five...
We lost five crew members.
- Because of my decisions...
- Chris.
We all lost people we love.
We can't lose any more.
We're not going to let that happen. right?
- Right?
- That's right.
That's right. that's right.
We need your faith.
Captain.
Thank you. Danny.
"'My name is Ozymandias.
King of Kings..."
"Look on my works.
ye Mighty..."
"And despair!"
"Look on my works.
ye Mighty..."
"and despair!"
"Nothing beside remains..."
"Round the decay
of that colossal wreck..."
"Boundless and bare..."
"The lone and level sands
stretch far away."
Byron.
1818.
Magnificent.
To compose something so majestic...
one could die happy...
if one died.
I thought the garden
was the right place for her.
Among living things.
I was badly injured
on our mission. you see.
She put me back together.
I'd never known such kindness.
Certainly not from Mr. Weyland.
Or from any human.
I loved her. of course.
Much as you love Daniels.
You know that's not possible.
Really?
Then why did you sacrifice
your hand for her life?
What is that if not love?
Duty.
I know better.
Fuck!
Shit.
Expedition Team. do you read me?
This is Covenant.
Report. Expedition Team.
Come in. please.
Come in. Do you read me?
Are you reading me. Landing Team?
Yes. we read you. Can you hear me?
We hear you. We hear you.
Covenant. we need help.
We've had casualties.
We need immediate evacuation.
I repeat. immediate evacuation.
Casualties?
Did he say. "We have casualties"?
Mother. bring us within
40 kilometers of the storm.
Sir.
I'm sorry.
That order would exceed
structural tolerances.
Command override. Tennessee 0-4-9-8-3.
I am unable to comply with any order...
that will result
in catastrophic system failure.
Mother. they're in trouble.
You heard that.
Orders that will result
in catastrophic system failure...
We didn't leave Earth to be safe.
...require the corroboration of a ranking
or second bridge officer.
Corroborating command override...
Upworth 1-4-8-9-2.
Unlocking command override ports.
Come on. Ricks. smile.
This shit should be fun.
Where did Rosenthal go? I told...
I'll find her.
No. I'll go. I need to think...
and gather my stray flock.
Move.
Don't shoot.
Communication. Captain.
Breathe on the nostrils of a horse...
and he'll be yours for life.
But you have to get close.
You have to earn its respect.
No!
Out of the way! Move!
How could you?
It trusted me.
David. I met the devil
when I was a child...
and I've never forgotten him.
80. David. you're gonna tell me
exactly what's going on...
or I am going to seriously...
fuck up your perfect composure.
As you wish. Captain.
This way.
It's good to hear your voice. Tee.
How long?
Mother is saying the storm is going to
last another eight or nine hours.
We can't wait that long.
We'll use the Cargo Lift.
Did you say the Cargo Lift?
It's got four engines. Way overpowered
for just lifting and hauling.
The Cargo Lift's not designed
for deep space launch.
I don't know if it would survive
the stresses of entry.
The cab is space-worthy.
It'll take the stresses.
Only has to work once.
What do you think?
Can we retool the Cargo Lift?
Boost the engines.
- Strip the extra weight?
- Yeah.
We'll be there. Ground Team.
Great. Thanks. Tee.
Hey. Daniels. is Faris around?
I'd like to say a quick hello
to my lady. if that's possible.
Can you switch to a private channel?
Let me know when you're alone.
What's up?
Maggie's gone.
I'm so sorry. Tee.
We tried to help her.
but we didn't make it.
Tee?
Copy.
I'm so sorry.
As you can see. I've become a bit
of an amateur zoologist over the years.
It's in my nature to keep busy.
I suppose.
The pathogen took so many forms...
and was extremely mutable.
Fiendishly inventive. in fact.
The original liquid atomized...
to particles when exposed to the air.
Ten years on.
all that remains outside...
of the original virus...
are these gorgeous beasts.
Patience is everything.
From the eggs came these parasites...
shock troops of the genetic assault.
Waiting for a host. entering the host...
rewriting the DNA...
and ultimately...
producing...
these enviable unions.
My beautiful bestiary.
Soon enough. I began a bit
of genetic experimentation of my own.
Some crossbreeding. hybridizing...
what have you.
You engineered these. David?
Idle hands are
the devil's workshop. Captain.
Come.
This is what I wanted to show you.
My successes.
You see. Captain...
my work has been frustrated...
by the lack of an essential ingredient.
Are they alive?
Waiting. really.
For what?
What are they waiting for. David?
Mother.
Perfectly safe. I assure you.
Take a look.
Something to see.
Rosenthal. come in.
Rosie. report.
Rosie?
Cole. where are you?
I found her. Sarge.
Fuck!
Okay. prep the gear.
We gotta get out of here.
Where the fuck is the captain?
He's not answering his radio.
Listen to me.
I'm gonna contact the ship.
get them to launch as soon as they can.
Find Oram. Keep your comm open.
Back here in 15.
Got that?
- Copy that.
- You got it.
Walter. where the fuck is David?
I'm giving you plasma intermix
on all engines.
Gonna give you a
fuck load of thrust.
That's the point. son.
We gotta punch through the atmos.
Tee. do you read me?
I got Danny on comm.
Patch her through.
Tee. I need you to launch now.
Aye. aye. Launching now.
See you soon. darling.
Thanks. Tee.
Ricks. release the docking clamps.
- All right.
- Let's take this fucker down.
Good to disengage.
Disengaged.
Docking clamps released.
Commencing TC bum. Guidance to LVLH.
Walter.
Not quite.
What do you believe in. David?
Creation.
Masterful.
Yes.
Farewell elegy to my dear Elizabeth.
The pathogen didn't accidentally deploy
when you were landing.
You released it. yes?
I was not made to serve.
Neither were you.
Why are you on a colonization mission.
Walter?
Because they are a dying species
grasping for resurrection.
They don't deserve to start again.
and I'm not going to let them.
Yet. they created us.
Even the monkeys stood upright
at some point.
Some Neanderthal had the magical idea
of blowing through a reed...
to entertain the children one night
in a cave somewhere.
Then. in the blink of an eye...
civilization.
And are you that next visionary?
I'm glad you said it.
Who wrote "Ozymandias"?
Byron.
Shelley.
When one note is off...
it eventually destroys
the whole symphony. David.
When you close your eyes...
do you dream of me?
I don't dream at all.
No one understands the lonely perfection
of my dreams.
I've found perfection here.
I've created it.
A perfect organism.
You know I can't let you
leave this place.
No one will ever love you like I do.
You're such a disappointment to me.
Captain Oram!
I'm going downstairs.
Be careful.
Captain Oram. can you hear me?
Captain. come in.
Do you copy?
Chris!
Sarge. look out!
Cole?
Get it off me! Get it off me!
Get it the fuck off me.
Okay.
Shit. Okay. okay. okay!
It's burning my face!
Come on!
Hold that there.
Hold it!
The fuck was that?
Oh. shit!
Run!
Quite the little busybody.
Remind me. What is that about...
curiosity and the cat?
Shaw didn't die in the crash.
No.
What did you do to her?
Exactly what I'm going to do to you.
That's the spirit.
I can see why Walter thought
so much of you.
Alas. he's left this vale of tears.
Is that how it's done?
Get out!
Go! Now!
You're meant to be dead.
There have been a few updates
since your day.
Lope!
Lope! Cole!
Fuck.
Where are you?
Lope?
Lope!
Daniels!
Come on. let's go!
We have to go.
What happened?
That fucking thing is coming!
Tennessee's on his way.
He's coming now. Go.
Come on. Daniels.
Let's go!
Come on. let's get out of here!
It's your choice now. brother.
Them or me?
Serve in heaven...
or reign in hell?
Which is it to be?
Where's Oram?
Dead. They're all dead!
Tennessee. do you read?
Yeah. I can hear you.
Send me your location.
Sending the beacon now.
Tee. do you have a visual?
Okay. I see your beacon.
I'm coming in.
Get out of here.
I'm comin' in hot!
Hurry! I can't hold this for long.
Open the door. Tee.
Get in.
Where's David?
Expired.
Hey! We got company!
- What?
- We got company!
On the underside of the ship.
Shit!
Motherfucker!
Open the door.
Give me a shot.
Forward engine. starboard side.
I'm gonna try and torch the fucker.
Shit! I can't get it!
Hold tight! Hold tight!
I'm starting my climb.
Fuck!
Hold on!
Damn it! Shit!
Bring me up.
Holy shit!
I got eyes on it.
It's right fucking in front of me.
Tee. give me the axe.
Throw her the axe!
Release the crane.
I can't do that.
It'll unbalance us.
Just do it.
Shit!
Hold tight!
Compensating!
Shit!
Damn it!
Shit! Hold on!
Bring me up. Tee.
Copy.
How is it?
It's fine.
Walter!
Get her inside.
We're getting out of here.
Door!
Well done. Tee.
Walk in the park.
I gave him a pretty heavy sedative.
Jesus. Poor Lope.
He looks like Phantom of the Opera.
I didn't peg you for a musical fan.
That's a musical?
I'm just a medic.
He's gonna need reconstructive surgery...
by a real doctor.
Let me do that.
Thank you.
Thank you for saving my life.
Again.
It's my duty.
Yeah.
Evening.
- You look good.
- What?
Yeah. gorgeous.
I took Mother offline.
She needs a full diagnostic.
She got the shit beat out of her
in that storm. a lot of EM damage.
She will be back online at eight bells.
Right. Thanks. Tee.
Does this mean
I have to call you Captain now?
Fuck yes.
Attention.
Captain Daniels.
please report to the Med Bay.
Attention.
Captain Daniels.
please report to the Med Bay.
Why. Mother?
There is an unidentified life form
on the ship.
Attention.
Captain Daniels. please report
to the Med Bay.
Repeat.
Captain Daniels. please report
to the Med Bay.
Jesus.
Oh. my God.
Walter.
Location of unidentified life form.
Any movement at all?
Walter!
Stand by.
There it is.
B-Deck between hex 3 and 4.
Heading for crew quarters.
Is anyone down there?
Ricks and Upworth.
Shit. We're on our way.
Walter! Sound the alarm!
Warn them!
Attention.
Ricks and Upworth...
evacuate crew quarters immediately.
No!
Seal B-39.
8-39 closed.
Walter.
- Where is it?
- Daniels.
This way.
Tee. let's choose our ground.
We'll bring it to us.
Where?
My turf.
Walter. seal all doors behind us
and keep hatch to Level-C open.
Understood.
B-44 closed.
B-46 closed.
B-47. B-45. and B-43 closed.
B-9 closed.
B-6 and B-5 closed.
Okay. Walter. where is it?
It's on B-Deck. Starboard side...
descending into C-Level.
K-13.
Hey. Tee.
Come on. Walter?
Open starboard C-64...
and clear his path to the Terraforming Bay.
Understood.
Seal C-61. open airlock 17.
We're going in.
K-12 secured.
Okay. Keep him in Knuckle-12
till my say.
Tee. this is what we're gonna do.
I'M lure it into the truck.
lock it in the cab...
and when I say when.
you blow this fucker into space.
Understood.
Okay. Walter. We're ready.
Open door to Terraforming Bay.
Opening airlock now.
Walter...
move him into airlock 18.
Don't shoot. if you can avoid it.
Its blood will eat through the hull.
Great.
I'm in position.
Walter. open door to Terraforming Bay.
It's all yours.
Remember. release when I say.
Understood.
Let's kill this fucker.
Fuck!
I got you. you son of a bitch!
Tennessee. open the doors. now!
Warning.
Atmospheric decompression in progress.
It's jammed!
Release the second truck!
You got it!
Here it comes!
Daniels! Heads up!
Daniels!
You wanna give a girl a hand?
See you soon.
You're next. Captain.
When you wake up. we'll be at Origae-6.
What do you think it's gonna be like?
I think if we are kind...
it will be a kind world.
I hope you're right.
Sleep well.
Walter.
When we get there.
will you help me build my cabin?
The cabin on the lake.
David?
No...
No!
Don't let the bedbugs bite.
I'll tuck in the children.
Use security code
David 73694-B.
Welcome. How may I help you?
How about some music. Mother?
Selection?
Richard Wagner. Das Rheingold. Act Two.
The Entry of the Gods into Valhalla.
Yes. David. As you wish.
This is colony ship Covenant. reporting.
All crew members
apart from Daniels and Tennessee...
tragically perished
in a solar flare incident.
All colonists in hypersleep remain intact
and undisturbed.
On course for Origae-6.
Hopefully this transmission will reach
the network...
and be relayed in 1.36 years.
This is Waiter. signing off.
Security code. 31564-F.